A Guide to the Edward Lawrie Tatum papers, Rockefeller University Faculty FA133
Rockefeller Archive Center
- Subject Files, 3
  - Neurospora, 1950-1972 1975 (Box 25)
    - Arrangement of Neurospora information from E.L. Tatum Laboratory
      - Neurospora culture requests, etc. (Box 25, Folder 1)
      - Neurospora correspondence, 1965-1970 (Box 25, Folder 2)
      - Neurospora miscellaneous material (Box 25, Folder 3)
      - Neurospora conferences, 1961 1966 (Box 25, Folder 4)
  - Oak Ridge National Laboratory (ORNL), 1957-1962 (Box 26, Folder 1)
  - Pacific Science Center Foundation, 1963-1966 (Box 26, Folder 2)
    Includes handwritten notes from Dixie Lee Ray, Director, to E.L. Tatum.
  - Population Control Problem, 1965-1971 (Box 26, Folder 2)
    Activities as scientist, Nobel Laureate (with other Nobel Laureates) and committee member to make recommendations on the problem of population growth over the world. In 4 folders:.
  - General File, 1965-1971 (Box 26, Folder 3)
    Includes T.V. interview (copy included).
  - Senate hearings on population crisis (Box 26, Folder 4)
    (copy included).
  - Papal petition and statements to Pope Paul VI, 1965-1966; 2 folders (Box 26)
    (copies included).
    - 1965-1966 June (Box 26, Folder 5)
    - 1966 July-1967 (Box 26, Folder 6)
  - Research Corporation Award (Box 27, Folder 1)
  - Research to Prevent Blindness, 1962-1975; 3 folders
    - 1962-1964 (Box 27, Folder 2)
    - 1965-1965 (Box 27, Folder 3)
    - 1968-1975 (Box 27, Folder 4)
  - Reviews of manuscripts (miscellaneous), 1957-1970 (Box 27, Folder 5)
    Chronological arrangement of manuscript reviews for various publications.
  - Rutgers University (Institute of Microbiology), 1956-1958 (Box 28, Folder 1)
  - Rutgers University, 1968-1971 (Box 28, Folder 2)
    Advisory board for research and graduate education.
  - SCIENCE, 1957-1972; 4 folders (Box 28)
    Includes some reviews by others.
    - 1957-1958 (Box 28, Folder 3)
    - 1959 (Box 28, Folder 4)
    - 1960-1961 (Box 28, Folder 5)
    - 1962-1972 (Box 28, Folder 6)
  - Scientist Committee for Voter Information (Presidential campaign), 1964 (Box 29, Folder 1)
    Includes news releases by E.L. Tatum (chairman), Oct 5 and 17, 1964.
  - Scientists Institute on Public Information (SIPI), 1963-1965 (Box 29)
    Activities to keep public informed on relevant technical problems and conservation of the environment. In 3 folders:.
    - 1963 (Box 29, Folder 2)
    - 1964 (Box 29, Folder 3)
      Includes: Apr 16, 1964 letter to Editor, MEDICAL TRIBUNE SCIENCE 144 (1964) 616 RI REVIEW (Nov-Dec 1964) 23-25.
    - 1965 (Box 29, Folder 4)
      Includes: AAAS report and Jan 6, 1965 letter to NY TIMES July 20, 1965 letter to editor of SCIENTIST AND CITIZEN.
  - Site Visits, 1961 1962 1969 (Box 29, Folder 5)
    - New England Institute for Medical Research for NIAMD, 1961 May 12
    - Institute for Cancer Research, Philadelphia for NIH. Tatum assists in assigning individual reviewers of "study section" for review of each investigator's work involved in Talbot grant application, 1962 September 17
    - Institute of Muscle Disease for Muscular Dystrophy Association, 1969 February
  - Sloan-Kettering Institute for Cancer Research, 1966-1967 (Box 29, Folder 6)
    E.L. Tatum, Vice-Chairman and 1967-1968. Chairman of the Board of scientific consultants.
  - Stanford Research Institute (SRI) (Box 29, Folder 7)
  - University of Notre Dame, 1960-1968 (Box 29, Folder 8)
    Chairman, ad-hoc committee on life sciences at Notre Dame, 1965-1966.
- RU Administration, 4
  - Subject files
    - University of Pennsylvania, 1956 July 6-August 1 (Box 30, Folder 1)
      Correspondence with University of Pennsylvania administration in consideration of appointment.
    - Administrative correspondence, 6 folders (Box 30)
      [Editor's note: A major portion of administrative correspondence received from Office of Faculty and Student Records].
      - Bronk, D.W., 1956-1969 (Box 30, Folder 2)
        Includes some personal correspondence and items dealing with RU academic council and senate.
      - Campbell, C.I., 1957 (Box 30, Folder 3)
        Activities for RI QUARTERLY. Includes RI QUARTERLY article 1, no. 13 on Tatum's coming to RI.
      - Flinn, W.R. (Business manager and Petrezelka, C. (Bursar), 1956-1963 (Box 30, Folder 4)
      - Registrar (M.E. Lucius) (Box 30, Folder 5)
        Includes RU catalog entries for Tatum laboratory.
      - Rockefeller, David (Box 30, Folder 6)
        Concerning search for successor to D.W. Bronk.
        E.L. Tatum recommends Joshua Lederberg and Eugene P. Kennedy for RU Presidency.
      - Seitz, F., 1968-1975 1972 May 10 (Box 30, Folder 7)
        Includes E.L. Tatum to W.O. Baker, Vice-Chairman, RU Board of Trustees, stating views on future of RU. Also includes items dealing with RU academic council and senate and with R. Nichols and C.E. Sunderlin on housing and parking problems.
      - Whitaker, D., 1956-1962 (Box 30, Folder 8)
        Includes some personal correspondence.
    - Faculty committees, 1958-1959 1966-1967 (Box 30, Folder 9)
      - Biomedical support grant committee
      - Committee on lectures
      - Committee on faculty appointments and promotions
    - Committee on biological sciences inch E.L. Tatum chairman, 1967-1969 circa 1 (Box 30, Folder 10)
      Includes 1969 May committee report.
    - Faculty and students club, 1959 1966-1971 (Box 30, Folder 11)
    - Honorary degree committee (Box 30, Folder 12)
      Includes presentations of honorary degrees by E.L. Tatum to:.
      - Donald D. Van Slyke, 1966
      - Fritz Lipmann, 1971
    - Miscellaneous activities at RU (Box 30, Folder 13)
      - E.L. Tatum involved in 1964 and 1967 visits of Russian scientists to RU, 1964-1967
      - RU seminar by Guiseppe Sermonti arrangements, 1972
    - Faculty committees involving students (Box 31)
      - Faculty committees for student courses. E.L. Tatum member of following: Primarily duplicated material (Box 31)
      - Faculty committee to consider graduate program in organic chemistry and biochemistry (chairman of biochemistry curriculum subcommittee) (Box 31)
      - Committee on genetics and evolution Spectroscopy committee, 2 folders (Box 31)
        - 1965-1966 March (Box 31, Folder 1)
        - 1966 April-1970 (Box 31, Folder 2)
      - Faculty committee for student interviews; oral exams; and theses evaluations (Box 31, Folder 3)
  - RU Course material (Box 31)
    - RU student courses E.L. Tatum involved in
      Includes Tatum lecture outlines and course planning. In 3 folders:.
      - Orientation lectures, 1958 January 27-28 (Box 31, Folder 4)
      - Molecular biology, 1958 (Box 31, Folder 5)
      - Frontiers of contemporary biology and related physical sciences, 1959-1961 (Box 31, Folder 6)
    - Student course material prior to RU, 12 folders
      - "Fermentation chemistry" University of Wisc, 1936 (Box 31, Folder 7)
        1 bound notebook. [May have given course as research assistant at University of Wisc] (Continued in Box 32).
      - Comparative biochemistry (Stanford), 1942 1944 (Box 32, Folder 1)
      - General microbiology (Stanford), 1942-1943 (Box 32, Folder 2)
      - Nutrition of microorganisms 1 spiral notebook, 1944 August (Box 32, Folder 3)
      - 1945 winter #106, 1 spiral notebook (Box 32, Folder 4)
      - Mutation and cancer lecture, 1949 November 11 (Box 32, Folder 5)
      - Genetics of microorganisms (Stanford), 1950 (Box 32, Folder 6)
      - #242 (Stanford), 1952 January 26 (Box 32, Folder 7)
      - Biology 148 Genetics of microorganisms (Stanford), 1952 (Box 32, Folder 8)
      - Biology 152 Biochemical genetics (Stanford), 1953-1954 (Box 32, Folder 9)
      - Biology 242 Comparative biochemistry (Stanford) ca. 1 inch, 1955 (Box 32, Folder 10)
      - Biology 148 Genetics of microorganisms (Stanford), 1955 (Box 32, Folder 11)
  - RU students dissertations, 7 folders (Box 33)
    - Fristrom, James L. Negatives and prints of figures only (Box 33, Folder 1)
    - Mach, Bernard F. (Box 33, Folder 2)
    - Reich, E. (Box 33, Folder 3)
    - Rifkin, M.R. (Box 33, Folder 4)
    - Shatkin, A. (Box 33, Folder 5)
    - Simpson, L. (Tatum not advisor) (Box 33, Folder 6)
    - Slayman, C.W. (Box 33, Folder 7)
  - Laboratory (Box 34)
    - Budgets 1955; 1956 and 1957 (Stanford), 1955-1957 (Box 34, Folder 1)
      Includes Stanford acctg records indicating expenditures applied to various grants 1956 Jan-Dec; 1957 Jan-Aug.
    - Budgets, 1957-1967 (Box 34, Folder 2)
    - Budgets, 1968-1975 (Box 34, Folder 3)
    - Budgets: Acctg records, 1965 July-1968 November (Box 34, Folder 4)
    - Equipment. Service contracts for lab equipment, 1962-1975 (Box 34, Folder 5)
      Includes service reports.
    - Isotopes (Box 34, Folder 6)
      Includes correspondence and records.
    - Personnel (Box 34, Folder 7)
    - Plans (Box 34, Folder 8)
    - Travel vouchers For meetings attended by members of Tatum laboratory (Box 34, Folder 9)
    - Vacations for non-faculty personnel, 1968-1973 (Box 34, Folder 10)
    - Inquiries for positions, 1957-1971; 2 folders (Box 34)
      Includes: post-doctoral positions and admission to RU.
      - A-M (Box 34, Folder 11)
      - N-Y (Box 34, Folder 12)
  - Grants, 1950-1975 (Box 35)
    Includes correspondence; applications; notifications; research reports and accounting records.
    - Grants at Stanford, 3 folders
      - NIH, 1950-1953 (Box 35, Folder 1)
      - NIH, 1954-1957 (Box 35, Folder 2)
      - ACS. Annual report 1954 Julyl-1955 June 30 only, 1954-1955 (Box 35, Folder 3)
    - Grants awarded to E.L. Tatum at RU
      - NIH, 1957-1962 (Box 35, Folder 4)
      - NIH, 1959-1961 (Box 35, Folder 5)
      - NIH. Accounting records only, 1964-1966 (Box 35, Folder 6)
      - NIH, 1964-1973 (Box 35, Folder 7)
      - NIH Supplement, 1971-1972 (Box 35, Folder 8)
      - NIH (Tatum and Wrathall), 1972-1975 (Box 35, Folder 9)
      - Research Corporation (Tatum and Scott), 1971 1973-1975 (Box 35, Folder 10)
    - Grants awarded to investigators in Tatum Laboratory
      Arranged in alphabetical and then in chronological order.
      - NSF (S. Brody) Acctg records only, 1966-1968 (Box 35, Folder 11)
      - NIH (E. Reich) Acctg records only, 1965-1967 (Box 35, Folder 12)
      - NSF (C.A. Williams) Acctg records only, 1963-1966 (Box 35, Folder 13)
      - NSF (C.A. Williams) Acctg records only, 1966-1967 (Box 35, Folder 14)
      - NIH (C.A. Williams) Acctg records only, 1966-1969 (Box 35, Folder 15)
      - NIH (C.A. Williams) Acctg records only, 1968-1969 (Box 35, Folder 16)
      - NIH (C.A. Williams), 1970-1973 (Box 35, Folder 17)
- Conferences; meetings; seminars, 1946-1975; 5
  Files consist of correspondence; programs; lists of participants; outlines, notes, abstracts and various drafts of addresses; some reprints; TV script and film reel. Includes participation in some television programs. Publication information cited for published papers [some not listed in Tatum bibliography].
  Arranged in chronological order in 7 boxes.
  - NYC, NYU Herter lectureship on "Metabolism and the gene" (2 lectures), 1946 May 15-16 (Box 36, Folder 1)
  - Brooklyn, NY Brooklyn Botanic Garden lecture on "The role of genetics in the nutrition of microorganisms", 1947 January 22 (Box 36, Folder 2)
  - San Francisco, ASBC 46th annual meeting. S.R. Gross and E.L. Tatum "The incorporation of carbon atoms 1 and 6 of glucose into protocatechuic acid" Published in: FEDERATION PROCEEDINGS 14 (1955) 221, 1955 April 11-15 (Box 36, Folder 3)
  - NYC RI morphogenesis discussion group meeting, 1957 April 8 (Box 36, Folder 4)
    Tatum "Some molecular aspects of differentiation".
  - Gatlinburg, Tenn ORNL 11th annual biology research conference on genetic approaches to somatic cell variation, 1958 April 2-5 (Box 36, Folder 5)
    Tatum chairs round table discussion on "Molecular basis of the cause and expression of somatic cell variation".
    Published in JOURNAL OF CELLULAR AND COMPARATIVE PHYSIOLOGY 25 (1958) 313-336.
  - NYC Barbizon Plaza Hotel, New York, 1959 January 6 (Box 36, Folder 6)
    Academy of Sciences conference on genetics of streptomyces and other antibiotic-producing microorganisms.
    Tatum chairs P.M. session and gives introductory remarks.
  - NYC Hotel Roosevelt ACS NY section symposium on valence, molecular structure and vital processes, 1959 March 6 (Box 36, Folder 7)
    Tatum involved in planning but does not attend.
  - NYC NBC TV Program Tactic on the philosophy of cancer today, 1959 March 17 (Box 36, Folder 8)
    Tatum participates.
  - Walla Walla, Walt Whitman College centennial lecture, 1959 April 20 (Box 36, Folder 9)
    Tatum "A century of progress in genetics".
  - New Brunswick, NJ Rutgers University Institute of microbiology 5th annual meeting, 1959 June 10 (Box 36, Folder 10)
    Tatum "Microorganisms, catalysts of change in biological concepts".
  - Charlottesville, Va University of Virginia, 1959 November 23 (Box 36, Folder 11)
    School of Medicine, John F. Anderson memorial lecture.
    Tatum "Molecular genetics - microbes to man?".
  - Jersey City, NJ Seton Hall College of Medicine, 1960 February 3 (Box 36, Folder 12)
    Tatum installing officer and speaker for Sigma Xi chapter of Seton Hall College of Medicine.
  - NYC Hunter College Bronx Campus 14th annual Eastern Colleges science conference, 1960 April 22-24 (Box 36, Folder 13)
    Tatum "Molecular genetics".
  - NYC NBC Continental classroom telecast lesson in modern chemistry, 1960 May 25 (Box 36, Folder 14)
    Tatum lesson //158 "Biochemistry of heredity".
    [See film reel #1-16mm sound kinescope. Can be run on any 16 mm projector].
    Includes copy of Wendell M. Stanley lesson #156"Nucleoproteins and viruses".
  - Chicago, Ill. 29th annual meeting of American Academy of Pediatrics symposium on current concepts of cell organization, 1960 October 17 (Box 36, Folder 15)
    Tatum "Genetics".
  - NYC Columbia University meeting of Torrey Botanical Club honoring B.O. Dodge, 1960 October 25 (Box 36, Folder 16)
    Tatum "Contributions of Bernard O. Dodge to biochemical genetics".
    Published in BULLETIN OF THE TORREY BOTANICAL CLUB 88 (1961) 115-118.
  - Toronto, Canada CBC Toronto TV interview, circa 196[?] January 24 (Box 36, Folder 17)
    Tatum "New genetics".
  - NYC Cornell University Medical College lecture "No title", 1961 March 4 (Box 36, Folder 18)
  - NYC New York Academy of Medicine, section of microbiology symposium on fungi and fungus diseases, 1961 March 9-10 (Box 36, Folder 19)
    Tatum chairs session "Metabolism and genetics of fungi".
  - Houston, Texas University of Texas Postgraduate School of Medicine 3rd annual Mike Hogg lectureship, 1961 May 9 (Box 36, Folder 20)
    Tatum "Molecular genetics, microbes to man".
  - NYC Cornell University Medical College Alpha Omega Alpha lecture, 1961 May 11 (Box 36, Folder 21)
    Tatum "The spore with nerve (s) ".
  - Cold Spring Harbor syposia on quantitative biology XXVI cellular regulatory mechanisms, 1961 June 4-12 (Box 36, Folder 21)
  - Moscow, V International Congress of Biochemistry, 1961 August 10-16 1961-1963 (Box 36, Folder 21)
    Session 3: Symposium on evolutionary biochemistry Tatum "Biochemical genetics and evolution" Published in: COMPARATIVE BIOCHEMISTRY AND PHYSIOLOGY 4 (1962) 241-248 and In: International Congress of Biochemistry, 5th, Moscow, 1961. Proceedings, v. 3. New York, Macmillan, 1963. pp. 178-186.
  - Rome, 2nd International conference of human genetics, 1961 September 7-12 (Box 37, Folder 1)
    Tatum chairs round table on microbial and biochemical genetics and presents "same title".
    Published In: International Congress of Human Genetics, 2nd, Rome, 1961. Proceedings. Istituto G. Mendel, 1963. pp. 509-511.
  - Colorado Springs, Pharmaceutical Manufacturers Assoc (PMA) research management meeting, 1961 October 23-25 (Box 37, Folder 2)
    Tatum "The gene and you".
  - Kansas City, Mo. Centennial convocation of Land-Grant Institutions, 1961 November 12-16 (Box 37, Folder 3)
    Tatum as RI representative attends dinner honoring Nobel prize winners.
  - Brooklyn, NY Downstate Medical Center Research Society annual lecture, 1961 December 18 (Box 37, Folder 4)
    Tatum "Some recent studies on the biology and morphology of the mold, Neurospora".
  - Madison, Wisc. University Wisconsin, President Kennedy's panel for mental retardation meeting, 1962 March 9 (Box 37, Folder 5)
    Tatum task force committee member on genetic aspects of mental retardation comments.
  - College of Physicians and Surgeons Columbia University symposium on basic problems in neoplastic disease, 1962 March 12-14 (Box 37, Folder 6)
    Tatum chairs session on viral and genetic studies and delivers chairman's remarks. Published In: Gellhorn, A. and Hirschberg, E. eds., Basic problems in neoplastic disease; symposium commemorating the 50th anniversary of the Institute of Cancer Research, Columbia University, and the 10th anniversary of the Francis Delafield Hospital, March 12-1, 1962. New York, Columbia University Press, 1962. pp. 69-71.
    [Not listed in Tatum bibliograph].
  - Westfield, NJ Westfield Senior H.S. Saturday science program, 1962 April 14 (Box 37, Folder 7)
    Tatum "Session on genetics".
  - Rutgers Institute of Microbiology symposium on informational macromolecules, 1962 September 5-7 (Box 37, Folder 8)
    Tatum chairs session on amino acid Code I and gives Chairman's remarks.
    Published In: Vogel, H.J., Bryson, V. and Lampen, J. Oliver, eds., Informational macromolecules, a symposium. New York, Academic Press, 1963. pp. 175-176. [Not listed in Tatum bibliograph] and.
    E. Reich delivers paper by E. Reich, G. Acs, B. Mach and E.L. Tatum "Some properties of RNA metabolism in mammalian and bacterial cells".
    [Same publication information as above pp. 317-333].
  - University of Chicago, Tatum delivers, 1962 November 13 (Box 37, Folder 9)
    Carlson memorial lecture "Genes, cells and organisms".
  - Rome, Food and Agriculture Organization (FAO) of the U.N. conference to focus world attention on the problem of hunger and malnutrition, 1963 March 14 (Box 37, Folder 10)
  - Philadelphia, Pa. Hahnemann Medical College 17th annual undergraduate research society day, 1963 March 20 (Box 37, Folder 11)
    Tatum "Molecular genetics - microbes to man".
  - Oxford, Ohio Ohio Wesleyan symposium on the control of human heredity and evolution, 1963 April 6 1965; [Bound volume lacks reprint] (Box 37, Folder 12)
    Published In: Sonneborn, T.M. ed., The control of human heredity and evolution. New York, Macmillan, 1965. pp. 20-34.
    Includes various drafts of Tatum "Perspectives from physiological genetics".
  - Guadaljara, Mexico II Pan-American symposium on pharmacology and therapeutics, 1963 August 7-10 (Box 37, Folder 13)
    Published in REVISTA DE INVESTIGACION 3 (1963) 27-54 [Bound volume lacks reprint] Possibly repeated at Mexican Society of Biochemistry.
    Includes various drafts (one a Spanish translation) of Tatum "Pharmacology and molecular genetics".
  - Washington, DC NAS centennial symposia, 1963 October 21-24 (Box 38, Folder 1)
    Oct 23 Tatum "Genetic determinants".
    Published in PNAS 51 (1964) 908-915.
  - NYC Pirquet Society of Clinical Medicine meeting, 1963 November 13 (Box 38, Folder 2)
    Tatum presents Pirquet lecture "Medicine and molecular genetics".
    Published in BULLETIN OF THE NEW YORK ACADEMY OF MEDICINE 40 (1964) 361-376.
    Includes Paul Weiss reprint "Introduction of Professor Edward L. Tatum at the Clemens Von Pirquet meeting".
  - Gustav Stern symposiums on Perspectives in Virology, NYC (Box 38, Folder 3)
    E.L. Tatum as member of program committee assists in planning and attending symposiums. Includes:.
    - 1964 February 3-4
    - 1966 February 7-8
    - 1968 January 29-30
    - 1970 February 2
    - 1972 February 7-8
    - 1974 February
  - NYC New York Heart Assoc symposium on differentiation and development, 1964 February 7-8 (Box 38, Folder 4)
    Tatum chairs session on roles of genes in development and gives "General survey".
    Published in JOURNAL OF EXPERIMENTAL ZOOLOGY 157 (1964) 3-8.
  - NYC CCNY lecture, 1964 February 13 (Box 38, Folder 5)
    Tatum "Molecular genetics, past, present, and future".
  - RU seminar on biochemical genetics for science writers, 1964 May 14 (Box 38, Folder 6)
    Tatum "Biochemical genetics".
  - Ann Arbor University of Michigan Medical School Human Genetics laboratory dedication, 1964 June 11 (Box 38, Folder 7)
    Tatum "Molecular genetics in human biology".
  - New Brunswick, NJ Rutgers Institute of microbiology symposium on evolving genes and proteins, 1964 September 17-18 (Box 38, Folder 8)
    Tatum "Evolution and molecular biology" Opening address.
    Published In: Bryson, V., and Vogel, H.J. eds., Evolving genes and proteins. New York, Academic Press, 1965. pp. 3-10.
  - "St. Paul, Minn Gustavus Adolphus 1st Nobel conference on genetics and the future of man", 1965 January 7-8 (Box 38, Folder 9)
    Tatum "The possibility of manipulating genetic change".
    Published In: Roslansky, J.D. ed., Nobel Conference, 1st Gustavus Adolphus College, 1965. Genetics and the future of man. New York, Appleton-Century-Crofts, 1966. pp. 51-61.
    Includes copies of addresses and abstracts by: Kusch; Reed (abstract only); B. Glass; Wm. Shockley. Also includes an exchange of correspondence sent by Shockley to Tatum concerning Shockley's address (one from G.W. Beadle with Shockley's reply).
  - La Jolla, Calif. Scripps Clinic Society of Fellows 3rd James W. Sherrill lecture, 1965 March 24 (Box 38, Folder 10)
    Tatum "Biology and molecular genetics".
  - NYC Travelers Insurance Companies seminar Tatum panelist in round table discussion on the future of man, 1965 April 19 (Box 39, Folder 1)
  - NYC Sloan-Kettering Institute for Cancer Research symposium on macromolecules and cancer, 1965 October 18-20 (Box 39, Folder 2)
    Tatum chairs session "Genetics and macromolecules" and gives "Introductory remarks" Published in CANCER RESEARCH 26 (1966) 1958 [Not listed in Tatum bibliography] [See bound volume 3. In June 1980 the bound volume of Symposium on macromolecules and cancer at Sloan-Kettering Institute given to RU Archives by Joshua Lederberg].
  - At RU RU/State University of NY symposium on the future of biology, 1965 November 26 (Box 39, Folder 3)
    Published In: The future of biology: a symposium sponsored by the Rockefeller University and the State University of New York, New York, 1965. State University of New York, 1966. [no inclusive pages in bibliography]. [Bound volume lacks reprint].
    Includes outline of Tatum "Physical chemical studies of macromolecules and their significance to the future of biology".
  - RU meeting "to discuss informally prospects for genetic intervention in humans based on the understandings and insights that have been obtained in molecular biology", 1966 October 1 (Box 39, Folder 4)
  - NYC Columbia University Club, New York Academy of Dentistry seminar, 1966 October 6 (Box 39, Folder 5)
    Tatum "The new look in biology".
  - At RU Russell Sage Foundation/ RU/Social Science Research Council conference on biology and behavior: genetics, 1966 November 18-19 (Box 39, Folder 6)
    Tatum attends one day (Nov 19).
  - Mexico City symposium on enzymatic aspects of metabolic regulation, 1966 November 28-December 1 (Box 39, Folder 7)
    Tatum "Discussion" on papers presented November 30.
    Published In: Stulberg, M.P. ed., International symposium [on] enzymatic aspects of metabolic regulation. Bethesda, National Cancer Institute, 1967. (Monograph, 27) pp. 243-245.
  - NYC RAI television program (Italian radio TV station) "The future of man", 1967 April 28 (Box 39, Folder 8)
    Tatum answers questions.